[
  {
    "sentence": "Gavinies published three books of sonatas, and several concertos, which are very highly esteemed by connoisseurs.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Gavinies",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q490205)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", I believe Have you ever remonstrated or. petitioned the Lord Chamberlain upon the subject?",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Lord Chamberlain",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q541755)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "you were a fool for giving credit thus to a dreaming Jansenist, and burning good music.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. Liddle officiated as leader of the band, Mr. C. Hancock presided at the harmonium, and Sir George Elvey conducted.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. C. Hancock",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q16030597)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Sir George Elvey",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q5541104)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Liddle",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He is speaking of the effect he observed a little Italian boy had produced by his accompaniment on the harpsichord at the Opera, instead ofthe usual performer.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. Viotti had some share in the management of the King’s Theatre.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Viotti",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q313188)"
      },
      {
        "span": "King ’s Theatre",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(Q1155331)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "They are purely British, and his acquaintance with any other school appears to have been extremely limited.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "of Rameau was represented in 1735, it was a balletopera Les Indes galantes.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Rameau",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1145)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Les Indes galantes",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(Q583297)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Benzamin Rogenrs, son of Peter Rogers of St. George's Chapel, Windsor, was born in that town, and after being a chorister, became a lay - clerk, or singing - man, of the choir of which his father was a member.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Benzamin Rogenrs",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q18546476)"
      },
      {
        "span": "St. George 's Chapel",
        "type": "worship-place",
        "uri": "(Q2449634)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Windsor",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q464955)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Peter Rogers",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The programme contained selections from the works of Bach, Handel, Mendelssohn, Cherubini, and Lefébure - Wély.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Bach",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1339)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Handel",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q7302)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mendelssohn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q46096)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Cherubini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q20721)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Lefébure - Wély",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q546919)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He now places himself on a level with a M. Beckers, who announces that he has pianos which will serve as objects of curiosity!",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "M. Beckers",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This gentleman is well known as the joint author of the Dictionnaire des Musiciens.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Dictionnaire des Musiciens",
        "type": "book",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He failed, likewise, on the first day of the Birmingham meeting, soon afterwards 3.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Birmingham",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q2256)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "the solo parts being sung by Miss Orton, Miss Wale, and Mr. Horniblow.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Miss Orton",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Miss Wale",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Horniblow",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. Mocre is the adaptor of words to this composition, which is a tirana, arranged by Mr. Bishop.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Mocre",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q315346)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Bishop",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1200639)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", Bow, E. — E. Carper is prepared to send Specifications for building Organs of very superior materials and workmanship.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Bow",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "E. Carper",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The Concerts of the Royal Academy of Music are discontinued,.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Royal Academy of Music",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(Q1144673)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Rameau was in despair, and thought to renounce the theatre.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Rameau",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1145)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Can the Irish members, moreover, assert that it has played St. Patrick's day”?",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "St. Patrick 's day",
        "type": "festival",
        "uri": "(Q181817)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "F. J. Amor, H. Lazarus, Walter Pettit, F. Ralph, P. Sainton, J. Thomas, A. White, and the Principal.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "H. Lazarus",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q5724751)"
      },
      {
        "span": "J. Thomas",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1701921)"
      },
      {
        "span": "F. J. Amor",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Walter Pettit",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "F. Ralph",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "P. Sainton",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "A. White",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Batiste’s Andante in G, an Offertoire by Lefébure - Wély, 2 Fugue by Mendelssohn, and Gounod’s",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Batiste",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q274231)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Lefébure - Wély",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q546919)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mendelssohn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q46096)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Gounod",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q180278)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Andante in G",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "There were aymptoms of weariness, to be sute, in some of the high tenors in the last piece, that noble double chorus from Mendelssohn's “Oedipus,’ and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mendelssohn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q46096)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Oedipus",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Sung during the Lent Season, at San - Carlo.. 27, “Odoardo",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Lent Season",
        "type": "event",
        "uri": "(Q82866)"
      },
      {
        "span": "San - Carlo",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q628491)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The following is a list of his operas, the words of which were written by the first Italian dramatists of the day.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "A new Edition of the Musicat Timzs, No. 3, price r4d.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Musicat Timzs",
        "type": "magazine",
        "uri": "(Q1757371)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Under the Direction of the Earl of Cawdor, Wednesday, April 24, 1833.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Earl of Cawdor",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q6224952)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Of the publication of Volume II. of Dr. Burney’s great work we have the following account:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Dr. Burney",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q547002)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "But there is something more in these assemblies than the strains that float from brazén mouths.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "On the same occasion, a quintett and chorus from Jerusalem delivered, an oratorio by M. Eberwein, which is still in MS. was received with much applause.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Jerusalem",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q1218)"
      },
      {
        "span": "M. Eberwein",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q215521)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The programme consisted of selections from the Messiah and Mendelssohn’s Hymn of Praise.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Messiah",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q207732)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mendelssohn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q46096)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Hymn of Praise",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q210536)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Lane, and Professor of Harmony and Composition at the; Royal Academy of Music",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Royal Academy of Music",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(Q1144673)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The Music adapted from SPINDLER’s HUSARENRITT by Louis Dien1.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Louis Dien1",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q19900926)"
      },
      {
        "span": "SPINDLER",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "HUSARENRITT",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Some think they detect already in Weber's “Preciosa” and",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Weber",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q154812)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Preciosa",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "We know nothing of the composer of “Fall'n is thy Throne.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Fall'n is thy Throne",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The first fart of the programme consisted of selections from the works of Mendelssohn.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mendelssohn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q46096)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "To be seen at A. Hunter; Organ Factory, 379, Kennington - road.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "A. Hunter",
        "type": "company",
        "uri": "(Q105564139)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Kennington - road",
        "type": "road",
        "uri": "(Q6390920)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Oakley, Esq., of Tavistock Place, and the late James Perry Esq.,. of the Morning Chronicle.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Tavistock Place",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(Q7689129)"
      },
      {
        "span": "James Perry",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q15047460)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Morning Chronicle",
        "type": "newspaper",
        "uri": "(Q2381797)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Oakley",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "that many composers who lose themselves in the clouds of mannerism and affectation, would imitate thewisdom of Sirletti, Asioli, and Pollini —",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Sirletti",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q102283903)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Asioli",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q892563)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Pollini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1351579)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Our academy will be useless, unless the patronage of the country is turned towards the establishment of an English Opera — an English School of dramatic expression.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Second Concerto and Di Tanti, 294 Kiallmark, his Le pas de Polichinelle, 1145, Are ye'angry, 238;",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Kiallmark",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q18671297)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Second Concerto",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Le pas de Polichinelle",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Original Instructions for the Violin, illustrated by Precepts and Examples, composed expressly for this Work, by T. Howell.. 507 XVI.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Original Instructions for the Violin , illustrated by Precepts and Examples",
        "type": "publication",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "T. Howell",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. G.’s ideas of tuition are however very correct, and his book will prove useful to masters.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. G.",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This enthusiastic composer, rich in talent, of the school of Bartolomeo Felici, wrote in the purest style.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Bartolomeo Felici",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q20757883)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "a concert was given at Brooke House by the choir of that establishment, assisted by members of the choir of St. Matthew’s Church, under the direction of Mr. Batchelor, the singing master at Brooke House.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Brooke House",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "St. Matthew ’s Church",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Batchelor",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Brooke House",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Piano Forte ed Arpa da L. Cherubini, » Almen se non possio, Canzonetta; Poetry by Metastasio; Music by",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "L. Cherubini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q20721)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Metastasio",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q29473)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Almen se non possio",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "She studied three years in the Royal Academy of Music, where she ranks high in the estimation both of masters and students.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Royal Academy of Music",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(Q1144673)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "I presume this is the same man who composed “Sally in our Alley.” —I am,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Sally in our Alley",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q104835875)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Here examples are given of the psalms of Marot and some of the earliest psalmists, whose compositions were even then considered as impudent innovations.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Marot",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q108926)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Between the years 1740 and 1745, we find but two complete dramas written by Metastasio, Antigono and Ipermestra, the former of these written expressly for the court of Dresden.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Metastasio",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q29473)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Ipermestra",
        "type": "work-of-art",
        "uri": "(Q18600820)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Antigono",
        "type": "work-of-art",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "court of Dresden",
        "type": "government-organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This charming melody has very recently been published in a collection (see Harmonicon for March last, page 60,) as a ‘Bohemian air,’ and marked allegretto!",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Harmonicon",
        "type": "publication",
        "uri": "(Q7738918)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. Duncan Finvay gave an evening concert at the Shaftesbury Park Lecture Hall, on Tuesday, the 15th ult.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Duncan Finvay",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Shaftesbury Park Lecture Hall",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This will serve to give some idea of the extensive field entered upon by Martini, and the diffuseness of that part which is completed.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Martini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q283651)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "the Bacchanalian Song from Spontini’s Danaides, and several other pieces too numerous to particularize.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Spontini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q168485)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Danaides",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(Q1751750)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Bacchanalian Song",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Vienna, Jan. 10. _ Donizetti has arrived in this city in perfect health.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Vienna",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q1741)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Donizetti",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q101698)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. and Mrs. Wood, it seems, are preparing to depart for America.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "America",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q30)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mrs. Wood",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "on application to H. Hagemeyer, Bandmaster, 12th Regiment, Cork Barracks, Ireland.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Cork Barracks",
        "type": "facility",
        "uri": "(Q5147345)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Ireland",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q22890)"
      },
      {
        "span": "H. Hagemeyer",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "12th Regiment",
        "type": "military",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Nevertheless, to be the rival of Carissimi he must have possessed considerable talent, both as a musician and a composer.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Carissimi",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q312686)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "himself, abridged and continued to his death, by Dr. Kitchiner; from which we learn, that _",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Dr. Kitchiner",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Since this note was written, a strong confirmation has been given to my opinion by a perusal of the History of the East Indies, from the French of L’Abbe Guyon.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "L’Abbe Guyon",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q2976789)"
      },
      {
        "span": "History of the East Indies",
        "type": "publication",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Her Majesty and Prince Albert took a part in ‘Die Elfen Walzer.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Prince Albert",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q152245)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Die Elfen Walzer",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Nor let us omit the performance of Grisias the Lady Norina in Pasquale, which was one of the most admirable specimens of comic talent ever seen on any stage.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Grisias",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q287344)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Pasquale",
        "type": "work-of-art",
        "uri": "(Q723941)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Il Barbiere di Seviglia,” the same season, at the theatre",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Il Barbiere di Seviglia",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(Q208659)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ": NgwcastLe - on - TyNE. — A most successful performance of the Antigone of Sophocles, with Mendelssohn's music, took place at the Theatre Royal, on the 21st ult.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "NgwcastLe - on - TyNE",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q1425428)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Antigone of Sophocles",
        "type": "work-of-art",
        "uri": "(Q241077)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mendelssohn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q46096)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Theatre Royal",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(Q7777436)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Sabadini also composed oratorios, the best of which was “La Divina Sapienza.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Sabadini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q3638803)"
      },
      {
        "span": "La Divina Sapienza",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The valuable scores of English church music, in several volumes, now in the British Museum, (No.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "English church music",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q4763552)"
      },
      {
        "span": "British Museum",
        "type": "museum",
        "uri": "(Q6373)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The chair was occupied en the occasion by Sir Thomas Gladstone, Bart.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Sir Thomas Gladstone",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q7529140)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Bart",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The three last operas written by Metastasio were, Il Trionfo di Clelia, in 1762;",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Metastasio",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q29473)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Il Trionfo di Clelia",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(Q18748077)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "’s 24th Psalm, adapted to the English version, by W. T. Freemantle (and revised by the late Dr. S. S. Wesley).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "24th Psalm",
        "type": "publication",
        "uri": "(Q1628536)"
      },
      {
        "span": "W. T. Freemantle",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q8019310)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Dr. S. S. Wesley",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q746420)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Published by authority of the Lords Commissioners of the Admiralty.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Admiralty",
        "type": "government-organization",
        "uri": "(Q396266)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Though Mr. Viotti had long retired from his profession, he nevertheless retained ‘all his love for the art, and contributed every thing in his power towards its ATS",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Viotti",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q313188)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Here we return to the forced leisure of poor Italy.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Italy",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q38)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "all the friends of music and of generous culture in Baltimore.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Baltimore",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q5092)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "| tains a new two - manual Organ by Walker, of London.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "London",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q84)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Walker",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He left Moscow, ‘and returned to St. Petersburg, and there finding no means of paying his debts, he yielded to despair, and sliot himself.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Moscow",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q649)"
      },
      {
        "span": "St. Petersburg",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q656)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The number of witnesses examined was forty - five, among whom were Mr. Mash of the Chamberlain’s Office, all the proprietors and managers of the various theatres, major and minor, many authors, and most of the principal actors.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Chamberlain",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q541755)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Mash",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "On Monday, June 5, 1826, died Carl Maria Freyherr Von Weber.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Carl Maria Freyherr Von Weber",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q154812)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Cantate Domino and Deus Misereatur have been sung at each gathering in such a manner as to prove that the best music is that which most.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Cantate Domino",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q1326476)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Deus Misereatur",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q1689664)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", Arthur Sullivan, Mus. D., Cantab., the Conductor, and the Principal — Eaton Faning.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Arthur Sullivan",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q212692)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Eaton Faning",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q5331349)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "-‘Chureh that “we would desire to introduce music of a less lagnbrious character than we have alluded.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "‘WissEAcH.—The second concert for the season of the District Musical Society took place in the Public Hall on the 13th ult.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "District Musical Society",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Public Hall",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "‘Carron side,” an opera by Signor Liverati, was produced with success.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Signor Liverati",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q3767573)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Carron",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "For ten years Jarnowick was in great favour with the public.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Jarnowick",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1526160)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "and.regular employment in the sanctuary of the Lord, which is proved by the following quotation:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "A new symphony by M. Joachim Hoffman, a composition of great merit, was performed at that gentleman’s concert.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "M. Joachim Hoffman",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "in the Antient Concert Rooms, which was a brilliant success.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Antient Concert Rooms",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Musical Society at Cambridge, in the y Term of 1871, under the direction of Dr. G. M: Garrett.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Cambridge",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q350)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Musical Society",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Dr. G. M : Garrett .",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Telramund, who enters the bridal chamber to assassinate Lohengrin, is himself killed by the Knight, and before the King, and court",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The Philharmonic Society, founded here by M. Schénche, is going on flourishingly.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "The Philharmonic Society",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(Q1292443)"
      },
      {
        "span": "M. Schénche",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. Kalkbrenner’s inelange displays great taste, both in the selection and treatment. of his subjects.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Kalkbrenner",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q170270)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "“Qui est Rex Gloriosus,” Canon four in two, composed and dedicated to Thomas Attwood, Esq.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Thomas Attwood",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q2422110)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Qui est Rex Gloriosus",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He is desirous of taking this opportunity of expressing his grateful sense of both, and adding, that in his communication with, and visits to, Cambridge (for by?",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Cambridge",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q350)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Cadences for the order of the Administration of the Lord’s Supper, in compressed vocal score.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "There are few persons in this country, we apprehend, who are not now aware of the splendid donation made by the late Viscount Fitzwilliam to the University of Cambridge.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Viscount Fitzwilliam",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q7325692)"
      },
      {
        "span": "University of Cambridge",
        "type": "university",
        "uri": "(Q35794)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "We, therefore, heartily welcome Mr. Hall’s book, as a useful addition to the scanty literature on the subject.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Hall",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Norwicu.—The first Concert this season of the Norfolk and Norwich Musical Union was given in St. Andrew's Hall, on Thursday evening, the 17th ult.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Norfolk",
        "type": "festival",
        "uri": "(Q11991993)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Norwich",
        "type": "festival",
        "uri": "(Q11991993)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Musical Union",
        "type": "festival",
        "uri": "(Q11991993)"
      },
      {
        "span": "St. Andrew 's Hall",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(Q7586881)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The search: after these persons is redoubled, and a school for them has been established in the institution degli Orfanelli, which includes many.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "institution degli Orfanelli",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "reputation as a composer; and we have only to add, that the praises bestowed on him in the Musical Gem are not only",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "than those at St. Petersburg, not even affording him enough profit to pay the expences.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "St. Petersburg",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q656)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The vocal music was scarcely so good as usual — with the exception of the scena of Miss Rainforth.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Miss Rainforth",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q17355767)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "“La Cascina and Statira,” 1756; “La Conversazione, Artaserse, and Alessandro nell’",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "La Cascina",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Statira",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "La Conversazione",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Artaserse",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Alessandro nell",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "We can not speak too highly of the manner in which this magnificent burst of grandeur was rendered, by Mr. Sterndale Bennett and his able assistants,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Sterndale Bennett",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q201164)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Where are there a dozen living British musicians to be found who are capable of writing a genuine fugue?",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "passage, taken up by the other parts as a round, like Rossini’s",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Rossini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q9726)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "G. Benson, Ettore Fiori, Manuel Garcia, P. Goldberg, A. Randegger, T. A. Wallworth, and the Principal.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Ettore Fiori",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q55912552)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Manuel Garcia",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q333183)"
      },
      {
        "span": "A. Randegger",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q4712167)"
      },
      {
        "span": "G.",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIl)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Benson",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "P. Goldberg",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "T. A. Wallworth",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Italy also derived great benefit from the numerous families, and the wealth imported by this means.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Italy",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q38)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Trieste 67, 171, 212 Turin 236, 277 Venice 67, 213, 236. Verceil",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Trieste",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q546)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Turin",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q495)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Venice",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q641)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Verceil",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q5990)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Thornhill drew ail their portraits in pencil, and Prior wrote humorous verses under each.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Thornhill",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1681192)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Prior",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "THE fifty - third monthly Concert of the Grosvenor Choral Society took place on Friday the 21st ult. at the Grosvenor Hall, Buckingham Palace Road.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Grosvenor Hall",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(Q5610643)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Buckingham Palace Road",
        "type": "road",
        "uri": "(Q23891197)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Grosvenor Choral Society",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Théatre de L’Odeon. — A new opera has been produced here, entitled, Charles V. et Dugueselin,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Théatre de L’Odeon",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q1133501)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Charles V. et Dugueselin",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "the programme consisted entirely of a selection from*the works of the late Sir Sterndale Bennett.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Sir Sterndale Bennett",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q201164)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The artists engaged were the Misses Agnes Drummond, Josephine Pulham, Marian Haigh, Florence Wydford, and Messrs. Henry Guy, Theodore Distin, E. Stone, and Thurley Beale.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Theodore Distin",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q76098551)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Agnes Drummond",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Josephine Pulham",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Marian Haigh",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Florence Wydford",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Henry Guy",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "E. Stone",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Thurley Beale",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "We have an irresistible proof of the effects produced by these in the following passage, extracted from (Almanach général de tous les spectacles, for the year 1791, (page 61).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Almanach général de tous les spectacles",
        "type": "publication",
        "uri": "(Q3235618)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "It is used in many of the Cathedrals and Collegiate Churches, besides numerous Parish Churches in England.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "England",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q21)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mrs. Shaw sang the next piece, No. 17, with more grace and power of vocalization than she had displayed during her visit.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mrs. Shaw",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q3291051)"
      },
      {
        "span": "No . 17",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "“Lives of the Professors of Gresham College” is a list of musical works in manuscript of Dr. J. Bull, in possession of Dr. Pepusch",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Dr. J. Bull",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q511463)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Dr. Pepusch",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q371825)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Lives of the Professors of Gresham College",
        "type": "book",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Tuts Saltarello has a light and playful theme which can.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Saltarello",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(not in Wikidata)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He also performed two of Mendelssohn’s",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mendelssohn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q46096)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Air Suisse, with an Introduction and Variations for the Piano Forte, composed by H. Herz.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "H. Herz",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q572547)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Air Suisse",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Introduction and Variations",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "a revenue which many an English nobleman, many a German prince, will hear of with astonishment and envy.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "* Leader and Director of the London, Bath, and Bristol Phdharmoniec Coucerts.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "London",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q84)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Bath",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q22889)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Bristol",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q23154)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This instrument being very little cultivated here to any other purpose, its scarcity is sensibly felt throughout Italy.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Italy",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q38)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Dr. Anslem Bayly, Sub - Dean of this Majesty’s Chapels Royal.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Dr. Anslem Bayly",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q4770596)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Chapels Royal",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(Q1062692)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. Wiitson. — Owing to a severe domestic affliction, (the death of a son)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Wiitson",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Charles Phillippe Lafont, a very distinguished violinist, began to learn the violin with his mother, who was the sister of Berthaume, when yet very young.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Charles Phillippe Lafont",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q517502)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Berthaume",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "In spring she goes to Milan, where she has concluded an engagement with the Scala and Cannobiano as primo musico.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Milan",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q490)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Scala",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q5471)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Cannobiano",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q3982039)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Among the pieces were Beethoven’s grand symphony in bp, and the overtures to Don Juan and Reissiger’s Felsenmithle, all of which were exquisitely played.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Beethoven",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q255)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Don Juan",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(Q192039)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Reissiger",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q213894)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Felsenmithle",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "We will'now give an account of the 3 process adopted by Messrs. James Epps and Co., manufacturers of, dietetic articles, at their works in the Euston - road,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Euston - road",
        "type": "road",
        "uri": "(Q3308692)"
      },
      {
        "span": "James Epps and Co.",
        "type": "company",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "R. Smith lectured at the Athenzum on Thursday evening, the roth ult.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "R. Smith",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The Enthusiast, a Song, written and composed by F.W. Horn- castle.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "The",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Enthusiast",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "F.W. Horn- castle",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Venice, besides the advantage of having orators destined to educate the singers, had Gasparini and Lotti as directors of the schools..",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Venice",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q641)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Gasparini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q446955)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Lotti",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q168345)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This will delight the people of Manchester, of whose world of music",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Manchester",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q18125)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Handel’s habit of borrowing from himself is well known.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Handel",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q7302)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "the bride recently went through a similar ceremony as Giultetta in Gounod’s opera.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Gounod",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q180278)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "In truth a double source is now opening upon us — Germany as well as Italy.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Germany",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q183)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Italy",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q38)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "She addressed a series of letters to the Bishop of London, to the Dean of St..",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "London",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q84)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The “Adagio,” in C minor, is melodious, and contains sufficient contrast of style to prevent any feeling of monotony.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Adagio",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "At page 16, the rondo “Allegretto Scherzando con Brio (certainly the most effective movement of the whole) commences.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Allegretto Scherzando con Brio",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "the subject of the Air from a French Melody, composed by Pio Glanchettini.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Pio Glanchettini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q18819786)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "When Fenzi is absent, Guida is considered as the best.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Fenzi",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Guida",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "But in the “Studii of Palestrina,” -a manvscript, procured at Rome by Dr. Burney, containing chants by the great composers of his time, are some, by.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Rome",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q220)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Dr. Burney",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q547002)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Studii of Palestrina",
        "type": "book",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "From what we know of Mr. Forde’s general abilities, we should think him far more fit for the task than any else one who has undertaken it;",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Forde",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "It is in this point of view that we ought to regard the revolution effected by Rossini in the music of Naples, as well as: its novel results.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Rossini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q9726)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Naples",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q2634)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "One of the very best performances we have ever heard of the Messiah, whether we regard it in its vocal or instrumental character.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Messiah",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q207732)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Fifth, on the Counterpoint of the ancients and moderns, 46 pages.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Counterpoint of the ancients and moderns",
        "type": "book",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. Kalkbrenner’s concerto was the only piece in the last bill of any importance.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Kalkbrenner",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q170270)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "w ho were accustomed to meet there frequently, such as Pagin, Gavinies, Pugnani, Gi- ardini, Van Malder, Dominico Ferrari, & c.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Pagin",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q516496)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Gavinies",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q490205)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Pugnani",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q560926)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Van Malder",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q509130)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Dominico Ferrari",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1237139)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Gi- ardini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Roller and Blanchet, more enterprising than their predecessors, have exhibited an instrument that possesses many advantages.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Roller and Blanchet",
        "type": "company",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Among the gentle‘men now contributing to Concordia, are: —: J. Barney.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Concordia",
        "type": "magazine",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "J. Barney",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "I am marvellously curious to see the violin quartet written by Rossini for Ricordi, the music - dealer, of Milan.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Rossini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q9726)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Ricordi",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1046463)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Milan",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q490)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "(Of the Royal Albert Hall Concerts), for Oratorios, Concerts, & c. Address 2, Hallfield - place, Bradford, Yorks.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Royal Albert Hall",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(Q193639)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Bradford",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q22905)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Yorks",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q163)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Hallfield - place",
        "type": "road",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Upon the coffin was ‘the following inscription:: CAROLUS MARTA FREYHERR VON WEBER.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "CAROLUS MARTA FREYHERR VON WEBER .",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q154812)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "One of the principal pieces in Hippolyte et Arcie, is the trio of the Fates, one of the most beautiful compositions of Rameau.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Hippolyte et Arcie",
        "type": "work-of-art",
        "uri": "(Q1376211)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Rameau",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1145)"
      },
      {
        "span": "trio of the Fates",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "They are neatly brought out, in octavo, with clear and legible type, and their price is Gne Shilling.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "When Garibaldi raised the standard of revolt at Marsala, a number of volunteers.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Garibaldi",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q539)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Marsala",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q481514)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "the paucity of the English female singers — Miss Stephens and.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Miss Stephens",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q5052928)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "For further particulars apply to Mr. H. Keeton, “Registered for transmission abroad.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. H. Keeton",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1438256)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Highly commended — Annie Albu, Amy Aylward, Jessie Jones, Agnes Larkcom, and Marian Williams.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Annie Albu",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Amy Aylward",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Jessie Jones",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Agnes Larkcom",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Marian Williams",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Naples ‘possesses five great “theatres, where operas and plays a are performed, and two smaller unes, where farces are given for the amusement ofthe people.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Naples",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q2634)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Both artists were together in Berliz 1835, and in one of his letters",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Berliz",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q64)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "They are all tinctured with a certain degree of elegance and expressiveness, particularly these by Mr. Clifton, Mr. Crouch, Mr. Eavestaff, and Mr. Banister.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Clifton",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q6224338)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Crouch",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Eavestaff",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Banister",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Since Barbaja seceded from the theatre, San Carlo has thrice been in danger of being burnt down.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Barbaja",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q908235)"
      },
      {
        "span": "San Carlo",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q628491)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Variations, and an Introductory Prelude on some Passages from: the Incantation Scene, by N.C. Bochsa 4.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "N.C. Bochsa",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q251397)"
      },
      {
        "span": "the Incantation Scene",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ";; The Corigress was opened on Sunday, July 19, at 11 p’clock, A. M., by a musical performance in the Briderkizche.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Briderkizche",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Rachel would proceed to London in the month of June, and play at the St. James’s Theatre.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "London",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q84)"
      },
      {
        "span": "St. James ’s Theatre",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q7593475)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Rachel",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "last concert for the season was given by Mr. Matthews’s Choral Society on Thursday, the 13th ult.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Matthews ’s Choral Society",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Signor Sabastiani, first clarinet at the theatre St. Carlo at Naples, is arrived in Paris.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Signor Sabastiani",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q109802688)"
      },
      {
        "span": "St. Carlo",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q628491)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Naples",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q2634)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Paris",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q90)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The predominant feature of Spohr’s music is a voluptuous monotony — a luxury indeed, but a vicious one.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Spohr",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q57226)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "but, after all, why not have given a symphony or overture of Haydn or Mozart?",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Haydn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q7349)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mozart",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q254)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", Professor of Harmony at the Royal Academy of Music, and Organist to the Honourable Society of Lincoln’s - Inn.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Royal Academy of Music",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(Q1144673)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Honourable Society of Lincoln’s - Inn .",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(Q69482)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "A new organ of 13 stops has recently been built for Charleston Presbyterian Church, so that the use of this noble instrument appears to be spreading among our transatlantic brethren.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Charleston Presbyterian Church",
        "type": "worship-place",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "M. Spohr has produced at Cassel a new opera, named, Pietra @ Albano.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "M. Spohr",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q57226)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Cassel",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q2865)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Pietra @ Albano",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The music consisted of a selection from The Seasons of Haydn, and the whole of Beethoven’s Mount of Olives.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "The Seasons",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q970337)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Haydn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q7349)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Beethoven",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q255)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mount of Olives",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q1087216)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Adelina Patti — for that will continue to be her professional.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Adelina Patti",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q234166)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The boy was traced to Milan, but Mr. S. was deterred by the expence from prosecuting, and was compelled to sit down under.the loss of the. entire sum.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Milan",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q490)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. S.",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "These two operas, and also two odes to Anacreon set to the Greek text, are the only fruits of our author's pen in the year 1799.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Anacreon",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q213484)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Sketch of the State of Music i in London — August, 1826..... 13)",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "London",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q84)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Rome has three great theatres; Argentina, Tor di Nona, and Valle.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Rome",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q220)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Argentina",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q588377)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Tor di Nona",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q3516772)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Valle",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q1109934)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Grazioli (who must not be confounded with the composer of the same name, who died at Venice in 1820). has published several operas and some sacred music.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Grazioli",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1525873)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Venice",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q641)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Engagements to be addressed St. Mark's Villa, Newnham Croft, Cambridge.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Newnham Croft",
        "type": "city-district",
        "uri": "(Q7018643)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Cambridge",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q350)"
      },
      {
        "span": "St. Mark 's Villa",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "M. Bochsa takes some trouble to present new compositions to the public; but he does not exercise much judgment'in the selection of them.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "M. Bochsa",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q251397)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This Edition has been revised, and Passages for the additional Keys arranged for Piano Fortes up to C, by Mr. Moscheles.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Moscheles",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q159551)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The barred recitative in F minor is very happy, and the allegretto in F major charmingly simple, fresh, and vocal.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", “La Cenerentola,” 1817, Carnivale, \" Performed in the theatre Valli, at Rome.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "La Cenerentola",
        "type": "work-of-art",
        "uri": "(Q176700)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Valli",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q1109934)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Rome",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q220)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The exquisite drollery of Levassor and John Parry were highly relished.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "John Parry",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q3399352)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Levassor",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Anthem written for the Consecration of Trinity Chapel, New York, April 17, 1855.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Trinity Chapel",
        "type": "worship-place",
        "uri": "(Q7842633)"
      },
      {
        "span": "New York",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q60)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The latitude which the Catholic Service allows to devotional expression must however be taken into - account, for the style is not that of the Protestant Cathedral.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The reception of the work was most enthusiastic, Dr. Bridge receiving quite an ovation at the close of the Oratorio.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Dr. Bridge",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q5497415)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Oratorio",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The first part of the chapter is occupied by a short dissertation on the difference which must have existed between the psalm. and the song, as they are used in the Bible.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "psalm",
        "type": "books",
        "uri": "(Q41064)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Bible",
        "type": "book",
        "uri": "(Q1845)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The Societa Filodramatica is about to produce Bellini’s opera, I Montecchi e Capuleti.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Bellini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q170209)"
      },
      {
        "span": "I Montecchi e Capuleti",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(Q1071307)"
      },
      {
        "span": "The Societa Filodramatica",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "we are moved only by admiration of the talents of Madame Pasta or Mademoiselle Sontag, displayed in executing the innumerable flights, arpeggios, and cadenzas which are allotted to them.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Madame Pasta",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q240963)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mademoiselle Sontag",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q64098)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "only that the name of the author had been misprinted Caffiat, instead of Caffiaux.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Caffiaux",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "the Philharmonic and the Antient being the only institutions that can",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Antient",
        "type": "event",
        "uri": "(Q17510840)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Philharmonic",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Ramsay was an acute observer of the character and manners of the Scottish peasantry, and has produced many pleasing and humorous sketches of the habits and sentiments peculiar to that race.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Ramsay",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q654775)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "2 viclins, viola, cello, basso, 2 piccolos, 2 oboes, 2 clarinets, 2 bassoons, 2 horns, 3 trombones, 2 ophicleides, tympani, cymbals, 2trumpets, big drum.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "AT a meeting of the supporters of the National Training School of Music, held at the Mansion House on the 23rd ult.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "National Training School of Music",
        "type": "school",
        "uri": "(Q55082727)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mansion House",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(Q1786933)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Zahn was a native of Rotenbourg sur le Tauber, in Franconia.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Rotenbourg sur le Tauber",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q153494)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Franconia",
        "type": "local-region",
        "uri": "(Q150907)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Zahn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "When seated one evening, happy in the society of his friends, he was visited by an order from the minister, commanding him to quit England immediately.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "England",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q21)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "To Mr. Willert Beale, the founder of these meetings, 8.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Willert Beale",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q7795125)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Dr. Barry, in acknowledging the gift, said that he regarded it as an expression of unity and co - operation between the members of the choir and himself, and thanked the Society for so kind a mark of appreciation of his services.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Dr. Barry",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Society",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Various portions of this Opera are now printed for the first time in England, making this the only English Pianoforte Score which agrees with the Composer's Original Score.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "England",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q21)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", ee OF the principles adopted by Handel in his employment of such phrases, 1 hope I have given a clear and sufficient demonstration in my last letter.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Handel",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q7302)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "What a clever fellow, too, the Emperor of the Moon and China",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "China",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q148)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Franz Liszt played this piece once with such mighty power and passion, such eloquence and truth, as I never heard before, probably never shall hear again.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Franz Liszt",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q41309)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "3- SEVEN VOCAL DUETS, by Bellini, S. Glover, Macfarren, Donizetti, & c..",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Bellini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q170209)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Macfarren",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1374708)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Donizetti",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q101698)"
      },
      {
        "span": "S. Glover",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Meantime, we Believe that we are correct in asserting that Dr. Sullivan has resigned his post as Musical Director.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Dr. Sullivan",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", Mr. Joseph Skeaf, the president, occupied the chair, Mr. William Laidlaw and Mr. T. Armstrong vicechairmen.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. William Laidlaw",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q8014247)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Joseph Skeaf",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. T. Armstrong",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "‘' In Memoriam” is a commonplace melody, with a commonplace accompaniment; yet there.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "In Memoriam",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "In 1760 he sent him to Paris, and he there took lessons of Capron, and at the same time studied composition under Gossec.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Paris",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q90)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Capron",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q120697)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Gossec",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q313667)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "As the, Music is at least fairly appropriate to the original Latin words, it may be imagined that it is grotesquely unsuited to the English.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The church of Santa Maria Maggiore, the third in rank, had as chapel master the Maestro del Fante, who has now been dead some years.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Santa Maria Maggiore",
        "type": "worship-place",
        "uri": "(Q186282)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Maestro del Fante",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q18416097)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The vocalists were the Misses C. Novello, Rainforth, and Mrs. Alfred Shaw; Messrs. Braham, Phillips, Bennett, Walton, and J. Isherwood.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "C. Novello",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q4322567)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Rainforth",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q17355767)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Alfred Shaw",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q3291051)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Braham",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1699393)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Bennett",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q201164)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Phillips",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Walton",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "J. Isherwood",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This is one of the very few things that reconcile us to the belief of the possibility of introducing legitimate finales inte English operas with success.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Francoeur was born at Paris, in 1698, and is mentioned as having belonged.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Francoeur",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1396905)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Paris",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q90)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "For some of the Harmonies to this see Accompanying Harmonies to Psalter Noted, Appendix 2 (above mentioned).",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Accompanying Harmonies to Psalter Noted",
        "type": "publication",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Now let our readers take the finale of any opera by Mozart, of the Fidelio by Beethoven, and compare it side by side with the finale by Wagner.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mozart",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q254)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Fidelio",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(Q193778)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Beethoven",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q255)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Wagner",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1511)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "It is expected to be completed in a year or a year LONDON: and a half.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "LONDON",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q84)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Tuts is the first new work by Mr. Griffin that has come under our view since we entered upon our critical office.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Tuts",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Griffin",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Cherubini never heard, any of the works Cherubini composed for Paris sung to his own pliant, beautiful and harmonious language.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Cherubini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q20721)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Cherubini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q20721)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Paris",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q90)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Weisse, in 1788, was bassoonist of the Chapel Royal of Prussia, at Berlin.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Berlin",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q64)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Weisse",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Chapel Royal of Prussia",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Jean Pierre Guignon was born at Turin, in 1702; but as he came to France whilst very young, and established himself there, we shall consider him as a French violinist.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Jean Pierre Guignon",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q337573)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Turin",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q495)"
      },
      {
        "span": "France",
        "type": "country",
        "uri": "(Q142)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Miss Minnie Curtis was highly successful in the songs and other music allotted to her, and Miss Adeline Payel and Miss Kate Wild rendered great assistance, and were deservedly applauded.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Miss Minnie Curtis",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Miss Adeline Payel",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Miss Kate Wild",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "to reach Missolonghi, where, after having collected more troops, he took upa position at Platea, and the memorable battle fought on that spot again testified his extraordinary skill, valour, and devotion.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Missolonghi",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q642810)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This, I understand, was the method pursued by _ M. Chelard, the. maestro at the German opera last season at the King’s Theatre.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "M. Chelard",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q924686)"
      },
      {
        "span": "King ’s Theatre",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q1155331)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Annie Butterworth, Hannah Edouard, Marietta Phillips, Marie Duval, Mary Jane Williams.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Annie Butterworth",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Hannah Edouard",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Marietta Phillips",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Marie Duval",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mary Jane Williams",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "De Begnis still occupies a place in the King’s Theatre.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "De Begnis",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q3770409)"
      },
      {
        "span": "King",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q1155331)"
      },
      {
        "span": "’s",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q1155331)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Theatre",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q1155331)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "For Oratorios, Concerts, & c.,; address 2, Hallfield - place, Bradford, Yorkshire.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Bradford",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q22905)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Yorkshire",
        "type": "country-region",
        "uri": "(Q163)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Hallfield - place",
        "type": "road",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "WE regret to have to announce the sudden death, from heart disease, of Dr. H. J. Gauntlett, on the a2ist ult.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Dr. H. J. Gauntlett",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q11925412)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Duet, ‘The streams that wind amid the hills,’ the Poetry by G. Darley, Esq.; the Music composed by Fanny Steers.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "G. Darley",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1450149)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Fanny Steers",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q104234927)"
      },
      {
        "span": "The streams that wind amid the hills",
        "type": "work-of-art",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He was chosen ‘to teach his instrument to the Dauphin, the father. of Louis XIV.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Louis XIV",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Places may be secured at the box - office; also at Mr. Mitchell’s Library, 33, Old Bond Street;",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Old Bond Street",
        "type": "road",
        "uri": "(Q892187)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Mitchell ’s Library",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "What has Mozart's portrait to do in the Memuirs of Rossini?",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mozart",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q254)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Memuirs of Rossini",
        "type": "book",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "But we will not praise Miss Rainforth over much, lest she, too, should become spoiled —",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Miss Rainforth",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q17355767)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", Paer’s beautiful little duet, is better in its original form, than in that which is now given to it.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Paer",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q533022)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Of Handel's efforts in oratorio we had also a full account; those gigantic. works, written after he had passed his fifty - third year.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Handel",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q7302)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Beasley, Llewellyn Bagnall, Alice Mary Curtis, nia Sheehan, Johanna Ludovici, Beata Francis.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Beasley",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Llewellyn Bagnall",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Alice Mary Curtis",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "nia Sheehan",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Johanna Ludovici",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Beata Francis",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "His first entrance into the musical world was as a tenor singer in the Pontifical Chapel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Pontifical Chapel",
        "type": "worship-place",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "the music of which is the joint production of two young candidates for public favour, MM.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Lord Bacon, Addison, Dr. Brown, Dugald Stewart, and many others,. are often betrayed into unconscious absurdities respecting musical effects by their ignorance of the science.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Lord Bacon",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q37388)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Addison",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q206384)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Dugald Stewart",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q218254)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Dr. Brown",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "-Apply at St. Mary - at - Hill Church, Eastcheap, City, on ‘Tharsday evenings, at 6.30.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "St. Mary - at - Hill Church",
        "type": "worship-place",
        "uri": "(Q7594548)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Eastcheap",
        "type": "road",
        "uri": "(Q1790942)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. Weidner’s performance on the flute, as an executionist, is truly wonderful.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Weidner",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Sir W. Jones, in his Catalogue of Manuscripts, deposited in the library of the Royal Society, gives us the names of some treatises in the Hindustanee language, which of course have never been translated..",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Sir W. Jones",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q273969)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Royal Society",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(Q123885)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Hindustanee",
        "type": "language",
        "uri": "(Q11051)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Catalogue of Manuscripts",
        "type": "publication",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This will be the eighth season of this Society, whick is under the conductorship of Mr. F. N. Lohr.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Society",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. F. N. Lohr",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The operas which he composed for the theatre Favart were successful for the time, but they did not live to be repeated.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "theatre Favart",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q872222)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The reception accorded to Mr. Brooke and the Choir'was very hearty.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Brooke",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "This amusement seems to have had a great attraction for Mendelssohn, who often entered into the - fun of it with characteristic zest.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mendelssohn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q46096)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He quitted Parma, and returned to Tartini, with whom he studied ull the year 1769.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Parma",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q2683)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Tartini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q108555)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", the other places of meeting having been, C arch Fenton, Abesford,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Fenton",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Abesford",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Melange for the Piano Forte, from “Il Crociato in Egitto,” by Frederick Kalkbrenner.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Il Crociato in Egitto",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(Q467399)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Frederick Kalkbrenner",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q170270)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The Yorkshire amateur meeting takes place annually, towards the end. of June, at Sheffield, Leeds, and York, in rotation; it having originated in the former town in the year 1809.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Sheffield",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q42448)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Leeds",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q39121)"
      },
      {
        "span": "York",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q42462)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Yorkshire amateur",
        "type": "festival",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "meeting",
        "type": "festival",
        "uri": "(NIl)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", Mrs. Mounsey Bartholomew, J. Barnby, H. Smart, G. A. Macfarren, Brinley Richard, H. S. Irons, Charles Salaman, Alberto Randegger, ].",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mrs. Mounsey Bartholomew",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q4766585)"
      },
      {
        "span": "H. Smart",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q466189)"
      },
      {
        "span": "G. A. Macfarren",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1374708)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Brinley Richard",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q4850963)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Charles Salaman",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q2959519)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Alberto Randegger",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q4712167)"
      },
      {
        "span": "J. Barnby",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "H. S. Irons ",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Sontag left Francfort for Brussels on the Ist of December.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Sontag",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q64098)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Francfort",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q1794)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Brussels",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q9005)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He afterwards produced an opera, entitled “La Sincerita trionphante,” which succeeded still better ‘tan the last: piece.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "La Sincerita trionphante",
        "type": "work-of-art",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He was born in Naples, where he studied the rudiments of music under Alessandro Scarlatti and Nicolo Porpora.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Naples",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q2634)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Alessandro Scarlatti",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q183087)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Nicolo Porpora",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q312788)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Did not Mr. Hawes resist the Lord Chamberlain, in the case of Joseph and his Brethren?",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Lord Chamberlain",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q541755)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Joseph and his Brethren",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q6288174)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Hawes",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. Linley proposed stating on his. song, that my quartett had been composed first.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Linley",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q5541748)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "My native town is a commonplace city cf central Germany.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "central Germany",
        "type": "country-region",
        "uri": "(Q524856)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": ", the fugitives got to Havre, where Sir Sidney was put on board an English vessel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Havre",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q42810)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Sir Sidney",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "the London Gregorian Choral Association held its annual Festival in St. Paul’s Cathedral.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "St. Paul ’s Cathedral",
        "type": "worship-place",
        "uri": "(Q173882)"
      },
      {
        "span": "London Gregorian Choral Association",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "In writing these Chants for the Te Deum I have divided it intoits doctrinal parts.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Te Deum",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q743376)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "WE are glad to find that, at the meeting in connection with the National Training School for Music, held at the Mansion House on the 23rd ult.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "National Training School for Music",
        "type": "school",
        "uri": "(Q55082727)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mansion House",
        "type": "building",
        "uri": "(Q1786933)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Grisi and her daughters, and the Marquis shook hands with his friends.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Grisi",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q287344)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Compiled by John Dobson, and for the most part revised ot rearranged by H. J. Gauntlett, Mus.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "H. J. Gauntlett",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q11925412)"
      },
      {
        "span": "John Dobson",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Liverroot.—A complimentary concert was given by the members of the Societa Armonica on the 5th ult. to their conductor, Mr. Armstrong, and leader, Mr. Lawson.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Societa Armonica",
        "type": "organization",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Armstrong",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Lawson",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Tauride,’ which operas. are considered amongst his most beautiful works, although they are tragic.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Tauride",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Luigi Rossi, Arcangelo Corelli, t with other great Italian compesers and imitators of Lulli at Paris, returned to their country with clearer and more distinct ideas of harmony.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Luigi Rossi",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q472714)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Arcangelo Corelli",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q164475)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Lulli",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1192)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Paris",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q90)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Thus the last seven years of this theatre are worse than the first, when fifty thousand pounds only were expended in the endeavour to plant an Italian opera.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Mr. W. Sterndale Bennett gave his second soirée on Monday evening, to a numerous, intelligent, and fashionable audience.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "W. Sterndale Bennett",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q201164)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "A COLLECTION OF ORGAN PIECE, “COMPOSED BY CHARLES JOSEPH FROST.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "CHARLES JOSEPH FROST",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q94766323)"
      },
      {
        "span": "A COLLECTION OF ORGAN PIECE",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "A Word or Two on the Flute, by N. W. James. creececess 53 VIII.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "A Word or Two on the Flute",
        "type": "publication",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "N. W. James",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "A new opera has been produced here, entitled Temistocle, from the pen of Paccini.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Temistocle",
        "type": "music",
        "uri": "(Q25410211)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Paccini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q357022)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The soio vocalists were Mrs. Bridge, Miss Pocklington, Miss E. Taylor, Mrs. Littlehales, the Rev. G. C. Robinson, and Mr. Fieid, all of whom were highly successful.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mrs. Bridge",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Miss Pocklington",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Miss E. Taylor",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mrs. Littlehales",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Rev. G. C. Robinson",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      },
      {
        "span": "Mr. Fieid",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "It is somewhat singular, that we find a passage exactly similar to one in Haydn’ s beautiful canzonet,",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Haydn",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q7349)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The drama of Ciro riconosciuto was the production also of this year.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Ciro riconosciuto",
        "type": "work-of-art",
        "uri": "(Q18325000)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Some reproaches are addressed to him relative to his melodies, as well as different observations, which interest us no more than Some reproaches did Rossini himself.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Rossini",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q9726)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The padre illustrates these rules by lumi « nous examples of the alterations of old melodies, and a table containing Tutte le Intonazioni dei Salmi.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Surely, then, the comparative share of Madame Pasta was not exorbitant, her comparative merit being considered; though, as I have before hinted, the positive sum, three hundred guineas, was at least double what would have been an ample compensation.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Madame Pasta",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q240963)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "The words are as simple as the melody, which however i is richly embellished by an arpeggio accompaniment, so varied as to de- mionstrate the fine taste of Mr. Bishop in such accompaniments.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Mr. Bishop",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q1200639)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "Ermione was written for St. Carlo in the same style; but this opera produced but little effect.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Ermione",
        "type": "opera",
        "uri": "(Q936702)"
      },
      {
        "span": "St. Carlo",
        "type": "theater",
        "uri": "(Q628491)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "He published some years afterwards “Nouvelle Methode de Violon, et de Musigue.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Nouvelle Methode de Violon , et de Musigue",
        "type": "publication",
        "uri": "(NIL)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "It will be remembered that at the taking of Capua, shortly before the victory of the Garibaldian troops, some sharp fighting took place outside the fortress.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Capua",
        "type": "city",
        "uri": "(Q58477)"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "sentence": "When given over by his physicians,: the Chevalier de Lorraine came to seehim.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "span": "Chevalier de Lorraine",
        "type": "person",
        "uri": "(Q916954)"
